Lukas Foss Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, circa 1926-2000 (Box 1-20)
  - Chamber and Solo Instrumental, 1930s-2000
    - Echoi (instrumental ensemble), 1961-1963
      - Holograph and copyist manuscript scores, Incomplete and revised scores for various movements; Copyist scores have annotations (Box-folder 8/9)
      - Sketches, Includes mathematical calculations (Box-folder 8/10-11, 9/1-2)
    - Eine kleine chance musik see Elytres
    - Elytres (instrumental ensemble), 1964, Early title: Eine kleine chance musik
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, Incomplete; Annotations (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Sketches, charts, and notes (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Fantasia (cello, piano), 1937
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/4)
      - Cello part (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Focus on G/C (string quartet), 1996
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Parts (Box-folder 9/5)
    - For 24 winds, 1966, Early title: Stillscape
      - Holograph manuscript score, Coda is missing (Box-folder 19/4)
      - Printed score, Annotations (Box-folder 19/4)
      - Sketch (Box-folder 19/4)
    - For Roger (trumpets), 1998
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Parts (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Frühling (piano), 1936
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Fugue in 3 parts (piano), 1946?
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Fugue in 4 parts (piano), 1946
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Grotesque dance (piano), 1938
      - Sketches (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Horn trio (horn, violin, piano), 1983
      - Sketches (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Horn and violin parts (Box-folder 9/11)
    - M.A.P. (Musicians at play) (instrumental ensemble, tape, referee), 1970
      - Holograph manuscript tape operator's maps, game rules, and performance instructions (Box-folder 18/2)
      - Holograph manuscript tape operator's maps, game rules, and performance instructions, Incomplete (Box-folder 18/2)
      - Holograph manuscript tape operator's maps, game rules, and performance instructions, Materials for Today, an early version of M.A.P. (Box-folder 18/3)
      - Photocopied tape operator's maps, game rules, and performance instructions, Annotations (Box-folder 9/12)
      - Sketches, notes, and correspondence (Box-folder 9/13-14)
    - Maine fanfare (brass instruments), 1994
      - Parts (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Music for six (unspecified instruments), 1977
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Ni bruit ni vitesse (2 pianos, percussion), 1971
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 18/4)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Paradigm (percussionist-conductor, instrumental ensemble), 1968
      - Sketches (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Percussion quartet, 1983
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Prelude, fugue, and riffs (string quartet, horns, trumpets), circa 1997?, Arrangement of work by Leonard Bernstein
      - Parts, Found with Anniversary fanfare, 1997 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Round a common center (piano quartet/quintet, with optional voice or narrator), 1979
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Saxophone quartet, 1985
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Solo (piano), 1981, For Yvar Mikhashoff
      - Holograph manuscript score, Includes coda material for Solo observed (Box-folder 18/6)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, Annotations (Box-folder 18/6)
      - Sketches, Includes coda material for Solo observed (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Solo observed (piano, instrumental ensemble), 1982 see Solo
    - Sonata for violin and piano, 1938
      - Violin part (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Stillscape see For 24 winds
    - String quartet, 1936
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, First movement only (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Parts (Box-folder 10/8)
    - String quartet no. 1, 1947
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/9)
    - String quartet no. 2 see Divertissement pour Mica
    - String quartet no. 3, 1975
      - Sketches (Box-folder 10/10)
      - Parts (Box-folder 10/10)
    - String quartet no. 4, 1998
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Parts, Fifth movement only (Box-folder 10/11)
    - String quartet no. 5, 2000
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML30.3c.F68 no. 1
      - Sketches (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Tashi (clarinet, piano quintet), 1986 see also Concerto for clarinet and orchestra no. 2
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 18/8)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Tashi. Rondo (clarinet, piano), 1999 see also Anne Frank
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 11/1)
      - Clarinet part (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Three pieces (violin, piano), 1944 see also Three American pieces
      - Sketches (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Clarinet part, Violin part, designated for performance on clarinet; "Early song" and "Dedication" only (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Today see M.A.P.
    - Trio (flute, violin, piano), 1930s
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, Pages are stuck together and have eroded (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Violin and flute parts, Pages are stuck together and have eroded (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Trio for flute, clarinet, and bassoon, 1937?
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores, One score is missing the fifth movement (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Valentine (flute, piano), 1996
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Sketch (Box-folder 11/5)
    - War and peace (organ), 1995
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score, Annotations (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Sketches (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Miscellany, circa 1926-1980
    - Composition class assignments, undated
      - Sketches (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Composition exercises with Paul Hindemith, 1940
      - Manuscripts in the hands of Hindemith and Foss (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Composition exercises with Rosario Scalero, 1937-1938
      - Holograph manuscript (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Miscellaneous early works, circa 1926-1938
      - Holograph manuscript scores and sketches (Box-folder 12/1-4)
    - Music composed for Lukas Foss, 1962, 1980
      - Manuscript score in the hand of Witold Lutoslawski, Short composition for Foss' birthday, 1962 (Box-folder 12/5)
      - Photocopied manuscript violin cadenza in the hand of Albert Markov, Inscribed from Markov to Foss, 1980 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Wanderer's song (voices), 1974
      - Manuscript score in an unidentified hand, In caption: Pnina [Salzman?] (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Unidentified early works, circa 1926-1938
      - Scores, sketches, and fragments (Box-folder 12/7-8)
    - Unidentified, undated
      - Fragments (Box-folder 12/9-10, 13/14)
- Correspondence, 1929-1999 (Box 21-22)
  - Anderson, Gillian B., 1981 (Box-folder 21/1)
  - Andriessen, Louis, 1964, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Babbitt, Milton, undated (Box-folder 21/3)
  - Berio, Luciano, 1961-1966, 1989 (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1946, 1956-1958, 1967-1982, 1989 (Box-folder 21/5)
  - Bolcolm, William, 1984 (Box-folder 21/6)
  - Boulez, Pierre, 1963-1964, 1985 (Box-folder 21/7)
  - Brant, Henry, undated (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Cage, John, 1971, 1978 (Box-folder 21/9)
  - Carter, Elliott, 1962, 1974 (Box-folder 21/10)
  - Castiglioni, Niccolo, 1967 and undated (Box-folder 21/11)
  - Cohn, Arthur, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 21/12)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1943, 1962, 1970-1976, 1983 (Box-folder 21/13)
  - Corigliano, John, 1984 (Box-folder 21/14)
  - Corso, Gregory, undated (Box-folder 21/15)
  - Cowell, Henry, 1964 (Box-folder 21/16)
  - Crumb, George, 1963-1964, 1979 (Box-folder 21/17)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1965 (Box-folder 21/18)
  - Del Tredici, David, 1983 and undated (Box-folder 21/19)
  - Dlugoszcwski, Lucia, 1966, 1979 (Box-folder 21/20)
  - Druckman, Jacob, 1964, 1988 (Box-folder 21/21)
  - Fleischmann, Ernest, 1980 (Box-folder 21/22)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1987 (Box-folder 21/23)
  - Freier, Recha, undated (Box-folder 21/24)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1986 (Box-folder 21/25)
  - Glass, Phillip, 1977 (Box-folder 21/26)
  - Gottlieb, Jack, 1973 (Box-folder 21/27)
  - Gould, Glenn, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 21/28)
  - Gould, Morton (Box-folder 21/29)
  - Hindemith, Gertrude, 1964 (Box-folder 21/30)
  - Hindemith, Paul, 1940 (Box-folder 21/31)
  - Isenberg, Ellin, 1985 (Box-folder 21/32)
  - Kagel, Mauricio, 1962-1971, 1990 (Box-folder 21/33)
  - Kaplan, Jacob, 1980 (Box-folder 21/34)
  - Kilar, Wojciech, 1964 (Box-folder 21/35)
  - Knussen, Oliver, 1989 (Box-folder 21/36)
  - Lachenmann, Helmut, 1990 (Box-folder 21/37)
  - Levine, James, 1980 (Box-folder 21/38)
  - Lutoslowski, Witold, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 21/39)
  - Maazel, Lorin, 1980, 1993 (Box-folder 21/40)
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1971 (Box-folder 21/41)
  - Menuhin, Yehudi, 1982-1999 (Box-folder 21/42)
  - Meredith, William, 1980 (Box-folder 21/43)
  - Messiaen, Olivier, 1929, 1949, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 21/44)
  - Milhaud, Darius, 1973 and undated (Box-folder 21/45)
  - Miscellaneous conductors, 1980-1996 (Box-folder 21/46-48)
  - Miscellaneous performers, 1979-1991 (Box-folder 22/1-2)
  - Moyse, Louis, 1994 (Box-folder 22/3)
  - Nono, Luigi, 1962 (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Nordheim, Arne, 1970, 1982 (Box-folder 22/5)
  - Orgad, Ben-Zion, 1990 (Box-folder 22/6)
  - Ormandy, Eugene, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Ornstein, Leo, 1982 (Box-folder 22/8)
  - Papaioannou, John, 1964 (Box-folder 22/9)
  - Penderecki, Krzysztof, 1971 (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Perlman, Itzhak, 1986 (Box-folder 22/11)
  - Pousseur, Henri, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 22/12)
  - Previn, André, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 22/13)
  - Reynolds, Roger, 1970 (Box-folder 22/14)
  - Rivers, Larry, undated (Box-folder 22/15)
  - Rochberg, George, 1989 (Box-folder 22/16)
  - Rorem, Ned, 1996 (Box-folder 22/17)
  - Rosbaud, Hans, 1961 (Box-folder 22/18)
  - Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1966?, 1978, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 22/19)
  - Rudhyar, Dane, 1984 (Box-folder 22/20)
  - Sandburg, Carl, undated (Box-folder 22/21)
  - Schat, Peter, 1964 (Box-folder 22/22)
  - Schickele, Peter, 1984 (Box-folder 22/23)
  - Schuller, Gunther, 1974 (Box-folder 22/24)
  - Schuman, Henry, 1978 (Box-folder 22/25)
  - Sessions, Roger, 1962 and undated (Box-folder 22/26)
  - Smit, Leo, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 22/27)
  - Solti, Georg, 1980 (Box-folder 22/28)
  - Stern, Isaac, 1965, 1982 (Box-folder 22/29)
  - Stockhausen, Karlheinz, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 22/30)
  - Stoltzman, Richard, 1994 (Box-folder 22/31)
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 22/32)
  - Szell, George, 1964 (Box-folder 22/33)
  - Takemitsu, Toru, 1970-1982, 1989-1993 and undated (Box-folder 22/34)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1974 (Box-folder 22/35)
  - Tower, Joan, 1981 (Box-folder 22/36)
  - Vonnegut, Kurt, 1987-1988, 1997 (Box-folder 22/37)
  - Wolpe, Stefan, 1961 (Box-folder 22/38)
  - Wuorinen, Charles, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 22/39)
  - Xenakis, Iannis, 1963-1967, 1979, 1987-1992 and undated (Box-folder 22/40)
  - Young, La Monte, 1965 (Box-folder 22/41)
  - Zuckmayer, Carl, 1941 (Box-folder 22/42)
- Business Papers, 1940s-2000 (Box 23-34)
  - Aldeburgh Festival, 1978, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 23/1)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1978, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 23/2)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 23/3)
  - American Center, Paris, 1980 (Box-folder 23/4)
  - American Composers' Alliance, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 23/5)
  - American Composers' Orchestra, 1982-1983, 1993 (Box-folder 23/6)
  - American Music Center, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 23/7)
  - American Music Festival, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 23/8)
  - Armando Verdiglione Foundation, 1984 (Box-folder 23/9)
  - Asian conferences and festivals, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 23/10)
  - Atlantic Center for the Arts, 1991 (Box-folder 23/11)
  - Awards, 1982-1995 (Box-folder 23/12)
  - Bach performances, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 23/13)
  - Baldwin Wallace College, 1996 (Box-folder 23/14)
  - Beethoven, 1964, 1983-1993, Articles and programs (Box-folder 23/15)
  - Bernstein, 1947, 1978-1998, Articles and photographs (Box-folder 23/16)
  - Bogota conducting tour, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 24/1)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1948, 1970-1997 (Box-folder 24/2)
  - Boston University, 1998 (Box-folder 24/3)
  - Brazil, 1967 (Box-folder 24/4)
  - Brooklyn Music School, 1974-1988 (Box-folder 24/5)
  - Brooklyn Philharmonic Orchestra, 1971-1992, Includes programs (Box-folder 24/6-11, 25/1-5)
  - Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, 1963-1998 (Box-folder 25/6-8)
  - Carnegie Mellon University, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Center of the Creative and Performing Arts, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Chamber groups, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Chicago Symphony Orchestra residency, 1966, 1973-1974, 1982, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Cincinnati College-Conservatory of Music, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Cleveland Orchestra residency, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Commissions, 1981-1992 (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Committees, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Composer's Forum, 1979-1985, 1994 (Box-folder 26/9)
  - Composers Recordings, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 26/10)
  - Copland, 1983-1997, Articles and miscellany (Box-folder 26/11)
  - Curtis Institute of Music, 1975-1996 (Box-folder 26/12)
  - Detroit Symphony Orchestra, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 26/13)
  - Dorian Wind Quintet, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 26/14)
  - England, 1973-1975, 1983-1995 (Box-folder 26/15)
  - Experimental music technology, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 26/16)
  - Festival Casals, Puerto Rico, 1996 (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Foss Festival, 1989 (Box-folder 27/2)
  - France, 1990-1995, undated (Box-folder 27/3)
  - French correspondence, 1968-1995 (Box-folder 27/4)
  - Fulbright Award, 1972 (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Germany, 1964-1998 (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Holland, 1964-1992 (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Hollywood Bowl marathons, 1971-1975, 1996 (Box-folder 27/8-10)
  - Hong Kong Philharmonic, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 27/11)
  - Improvisation Chamber Ensemble, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Israel, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 28/2)
  - Israel Chamber Orchestra, 1964, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Israel Philharmonic Orchestra, 1973-1976, 1986 (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Istanbul, 1973 (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Italy, 1973-1993 (Box-folder 28/6-7)
  - Jerusalem Symphony Orchestra, 1971-1990 (Box-folder 28/8-9)
  - John F. Kennedy Center, 1980-1981, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 28/10)
  - Korea, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Koussevitzky Music Foundation, 1973-1975, 1992, 1997 (Box-folder 29/2)
  - Lectures and residencies, 1980-1997 (Box-folder 29/3-4)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1975-1985 (Box-folder 29/5)
  - London Sinfonietta, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 29/6)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Institute, 1974-1976, 1985-1987, 1996 (Box-folder 29/7)
  - Mahler, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 29/8)
  - Manhattan School of Music, 1972-1973, 1986, 1991 (Box-folder 29/9)
  - Messiah, Kleinhans Music Hall, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 29/10)
  - Mexico, 1971-1991, 1997 (Box-folder 29/11)
  - Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra, 1977-1994, Includes programs (Box-folder 30/1-9, 31/1-2)
  - Miscellaneous European concerts, 1965-1978, undated (Box-folder 31/3)
  - Miscellany, 1973-1978, 1989-1993, 2000, Chiefly correspondence with various colleges and universities (Box-folder 31/4-6)
  - Montreal Symphony Orchestra, 1969-1981 (Box-folder 31/7)
  - Mozart, 1973, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 31/8)
  - Musicians Against Nuclear Arms Inc., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 31/9)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1975-1992 (Box-folder 32/1)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 32/2)
  - New Music Concerts, Toronto, 1968-1978, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 32/3)
  - New World Symphony, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 32/4)
  - New York Philharmonic, 1964-1999 (Box-folder 32/5)
  - Norway, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 32/6)
  - Ojai Festival, 1962-1996 (Box-folder 32/7-8)
  - Opera, 1977-1990 (Box-folder 32/9)
  - Orchestras, 1974-1992, Articles and correspondence related to various orchestras (Box-folder 32/10)
  - Oregon Symphony, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 32/11)
  - Orquestra sinfônica brasileira, 1967 (Box-folder 32/12)
  - Piccolo Spoleto performance, 1996 (Box-folder 33/1)
  - Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra, 1989 (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Poland, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Portugal residency, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Programming ideas, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Publishers, 1978-1987, 1993 (Box-folder 33/6)
  - Radio programming, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 33/7)
  - Recording companies, 1981-1995 (Box-folder 33/8)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1973-1991 (Box-folder 33/9)
  - Rushmore Festival, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 33/10)
  - Russia, 1991 (Box-folder 33/11)
  - Sacred Music Festival, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 33/12)
  - Spokane Symphony Orchestra, 1993 (Box-folder 33/13)
  - St. Louis Symphony Orchestra, 1976 (Box-folder 33/14)
  - State University of New York at Buffalo, 1964-1970, 1982-1987, 2000 (Box-folder 33/15)
  - Stravinsky Festival, 1966 (Box-folder 33/16)
  - Tanglewood Music Festival, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 34/1-2)
  - Television appearances, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 34/3)
  - Thea Dispeker artist management, 1972-1987 (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Tokyo, 1970-1997 (Box-folder 34/5)
  - Turkey residencies, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 34/6)
  - UCLA, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 34/7)
  - Vancouver Symphony Orchestra, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 34/8)
  - Works lists, 1974, undated (Box-folder 34/9)
  - Yale University, 1980, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 34/10)
- Musical Works Files, 1980s-1999 (Box 35-37)
  - American cantata (Box-folder 35/1)
  - American fanfare (Box-folder 35/2)
  - American landscapes see Guitar concerto
  - Baroque variations (Box-folder 35/3)
  - Behold! I build an house (Box-folder 35/4)
  - Brass quintet (Box-folder 35/5)
  - Capriccio (cello, piano) (Box-folder 35/6)
  - The cave of the winds (Box-folder 35/7)
  - Celebration (chorus, band or orchestra) (Box-folder 35/8)
  - Cello concert (Box-folder 35/9)
  - Central Park reel (Box-folder 35/10)
  - Concerto for clarinet and orchestra no. 2 (Box-folder 35/11)
  - Concerto for oboe and orchestra (Box-folder 35/12)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra no. 2 (Box-folder 35/13)
  - Concerto for solo percussion and orchestra (Box-folder 35/14)
  - Curriculum vitae (Box-folder 35/15)
  - Curriculum vitae with time bomb (Box-folder 35/16)
  - De profundis (Box-folder 35/17)
  - Echoi (Box-folder 35/18)
  - Elegy for Anne Frank (Box-folder 35/19)
  - Elytres (Box-folder 35/20)
  - Embros (Box-folder 35/21)
  - Exeunt (Box-folder 35/22)
  - Fantasy rondo (Box-folder 35/23)
  - Folksong (Box-folder 35/24)
  - For 24 winds (Box-folder 35/25)
  - For 200 cellos (Box-folder 35/26)
  - For Lenny (Box-folder 35/27)
  - For Toru (Box-folder 35/28)
  - Fragments of Archilochos (Box-folder 35/29)
  - Geod (Box-folder 35/30)
  - Griffelkin (Box-folder 35/31)
  - Griffelkin suite (Box-folder 35/32)
  - Guitar concerto (Box-folder 35/33)
  - The impresario (Box-folder 36/1)
  - Introductions and goodbyes (Box-folder 36/2)
  - The jumping frog of Calaveras County (Box-folder 36/3)
  - Kakfa Tagebuch (Box-folder 36/4)
  - Lamdeni (Box-folder 36/5)
  - Left hand piano concerto (Box-folder 36/6)
  - M.A.P. (Box-folder 36/7)
  - Measure for measure (Box-folder 36/8)
  - Music for six (Box-folder 36/9)
  - Ni bruit ni vitesse (Box-folder 36/10)
  - Night music for John Lennon (Box-folder 36/11)
  - Non-improvisation (Box-folder 36/12)
  - Ode for orchestra (Box-folder 36/13)
  - Orpheus (Box-folder 36/14)
  - Orpheus and Euridice (Box-folder 36/15)
  - A parable of death (Box-folder 36/16)
  - Paradigm (Box-folder 36/17)
  - Percussion quartet (Box-folder 36/18)
  - The prairie (Box-folder 36/19)
  - Psalms (Box-folder 36/20)
  - Quintets for orchestra (Box-folder 36/21)
  - Renaissance concerto (Box-folder 36/22-23)
  - Round a common center (Box-folder 36/24)
  - Salomon Rossi suite (Box-folder 37/1)
  - Sanctus (Box-folder 37/2)
  - Saxophone quartet (Box-folder 37/3)
  - Set of three pieces for two pianos (Box-folder 37/4)
  - Solo (Box-folder 37/5)
  - Solo observed (Box-folder 37/6)
  - Song of songs (Box-folder 37/7)
  - String quartet no. 3 (Box-folder 37/8)
  - String quartet no. 4 (Box-folder 37/9)
  - Symphony no. 3 (Symphony of sorrows) (Box-folder 37/10)
  - Symphony no. 4 (Windows to the past) (Box-folder 37/11)
  - Tashi (Box-folder 37/12)
  - ... then the rocks on the mountains begin to shout (Box-folder 37/13)
  - Thirteen ways of looking at a blackbird (Box-folder 37/14)
  - Three airs for Frank O'Hara's angel (Box-folder 37/15)
  - Three pieces / Three American pieces (Box-folder 37/16)
  - Time cycle (Box-folder 37/17-18)
  - Two-part inventions (Box-folder 37/19)
  - Wanderer's Gemütsruhe (Box-folder 37/20)
  - With music strong (Box-folder 37/21)
- Miscellany, 1940s-1999 (Box 38-39)
  - Canticle of canticles, undated, Manuscript in the hand of Louise Talma; Transcription of: Gietmann, Gerhard. "Canticle of Canticles." The Catholic Encyclopedia. Vol. 3. New York: Robert Appleton Company, 1908 (Box-folder 38/1)
  - Poetry, 1975 and undated, Poems written for Foss by various authors (Box-folder 38/2)
  - Programs, 1951, 1960-1999 and undated (Box-folder 38/3-10)
  - Writings about Foss, 1940s-1990s, Chiefly articles and student papers (Box-folder 39/1-7)
  - Writings by Foss, 1958, 1964, 1981 and undated, Articles, essays, program notes, and draft materials (Box-folder 39/8-9)